Asaf Mazar

Behavioral Scientist





(714) 323-1108



Los Angeles, CA



www.asafmazar.com



www.linkedin.com/in/asaf -mazar



Skills

Habit and Behavior Change Intervention Science **Behavioral Economics** Experience Sampling/EMA



Programming

R (expert) | SQL (intermediate)



∫ Statistics

Multilevel Modelling Geospatial analysis **Data Visualization** Social Network Analysis



Education

Ph.D. / May 2022 (Expected) Psychology University of Southern California

M.A. / March 2020

Psychology University of Southern California

B.A. / June 2016

(magna cum laude) Psychology and English Literature **Ben-Gurion University**



About

Behavioral scientist with 7+ years of research experience in academia, industry, and policy. I use applied behavior change expertise and advanced quantitative methods to generate actionable user insights. I enjoy communicating complex ideas to both expert and lay audiences.

Experience

Behavioral Scientist

Irrational Labs | April 2021 - Present

- Led experimentation to generate and test value propositions for a leading health benefits startup. Analyzed data and presented results and strategy recommendations to stakeholders.
- Mentored a diverse set of companies in leveraging behavioral insights to increase user conversion and retention.

Behavioral Scientist

Catalyst Behavioral Sciences | Dec 2019 - Present

- Analyzed consumer data from the U.S., Europe, and Asia, using the resulting insights to shape product development and international marketing campaigns by Fortune 100 companies.
- Lead data scientist on a representative poll of Christian voters. Worked with non-profit leaders, public relations team, and media editors to communicate poll results in national and local outlets.
- Collaborated with a team of academic, industry, and policy experts to evaluate performance of a national wellness program (funding amount: \$ +1.4M). Designed and analyzed large-scale studies.

Graduate Research Fellow / Project Manager (2016-2017)

University of Southern California | Aug 2016 - Present

- Managed a team of research assistants running complex longitudinal field studies examining habits, behavior change, and nudges in domains such as exercise, voter turnout, and consumer behavior.
- Used quantitative modeling to analyze multi-method datasets.
- Published original research in top peer-reviewed journals and presented at international conferences.
- Taught undergraduate courses in statistics and research methods.
- Organized the "Science of Habits" interdisciplinary conference, featuring leading experts from the US, UK, Europe, Israel, and China.

Selected Publications

Media Mentions

Could Behavioral Nudges Help us Tackle the Climate Crisis? Financial Times. September 15, 2021.

<u>Trump's Overtures Struggle to Register with Religious Voters</u>. *Politico*. September 10, 2020.

White Evangelicals and Catholics may Finally be Opening their Ears. Washington Post. September 14, 2020.

Academic Publications

Mazar, A. Wood, W. (2022). Illusory Feelings, Elusive Habits: Explanations of Behavior Overlook Habits. *Psychological Science*.

Mazar, A., Tomaino, G., Carmon, Z., Wood, W. (*under 2nd review*). Friction Discounting: Americans Underestimate the Effect of Friction on Voter Turnout. *Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences*.

Mazar, A., Tomaino, G., Carmon, Z., Wood, W. (2022). Habits for our Habitat: Using the Psychology of Habits to Promote Sustainability. *Behavioral Science and Policy*.

Wood, W., Mazar, A., Neal, D., (2021) Habits and goals in human behavior: separate but interacting systems. *Perspectives on Psychological Science*.

Working Papers

Mazar, A., Tomaino, G., Carmon, Z., Wood, W. (*under review*). Distance to Vaccine Sites is Associated with Lower COVID-19 Vaccine Uptake. *JAMA Network Open*.

Mazar, A., Chochlakis, G., Kassaie, M. (working paper). Powered by the Will? Using Social Media to Explore Lay Beliefs of Health Behavior Change.

Haran, U., Moran, S., Mazar, A. (*under* 2nd *review*). Confidently at Your Service: Advisors Alter Their Stated Confidence to Be Helpful.